{
    "id": "ced94df4f5504311b01f6aa3a64fc0d3",
    "title": "Verbs And Their Complements",
    "exercises": [
        {
            "id": "73917428558a4bdcbd583125111f6efa",
            "title": "Verbs And Their Complements",
            "questions": [
                {
                    "question": "He appears to be very ……………………… today.",
                    "description": "Appear is a copular verb. We use adjectives, not adverbs, to modify copular verbs.",
                    "answers": [
                        "angry",
                        "angrily",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She doesn’t want to continue her studies. It ……………………. a pity.",
                    "description": "Seem can be used to talk about subjective impressions and feelings. Appear is mainly used to talk about objective facts.",
                    "answers": [
                        "seems",
                        "appears",
                        "looks"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "She seems ………………………… an attitude problem.",
                    "description": "We use a to-infinitive after seem.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to have",
                        "having",
                        "that has"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I hope …………………………. a good job soon.",
                    "description": "We use a to-infinitive after hope.",
                    "answers": [
                        "getting",
                        "to get",
                        "that I get"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "It is not easy ………………………… smoking.",
                    "description": "We use a to-infinitive after easy.",
                    "answers": [
                        "stopping",
                        "to stop",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "I suggest ……………………………. a lawyer.",
                    "description": "Suggest can be followed by an ing form or a that-clause. It cannot be followed by a to-infinitive. ",
                    "answers": [
                        "seeing",
                        "to see",
                        "that you see"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The doctor recommended …………………………… down on my sugar intake.",
                    "description": "After recommend you can write an ing form or a that-clause. You cannot write a to-infinitive.",
                    "answers": [
                        "me to cut",
                        "that I cut",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "The doctor recommended …………………….. a long break.",
                    "description": "After recommend you can write an ing form or a that-clause. You cannot write a to-infinitive.",
                    "answers": [
                        "me to take",
                        "taking",
                        "that I take"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "The boy insisted ………………………….. nothing wrong.",
                    "description": "We use a that-clause after insist.",
                    "answers": [
                        "to do",
                        "doing",
                        "that he did"
                    ],
                    "correct": 2
                },
                {
                    "question": "Now that I am getting older, I tend ………………………. things.",
                    "description": "We use a to-infinitive after tend.",
                    "answers": [
                        "forgetting",
                        "to forget",
                        "Either could be used here"
                    ],
                    "correct": 1
                },
                {
                    "question": "Let’s cut it ………………………..",
                    "description": "Here short is the complement of the object it. Object complements are usually adjectives or nouns.",
                    "answers": [
                        "short",
                        "shortly"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                },
                {
                    "question": "I find her attitude …………………………",
                    "description": "Here strange is the complement of the object attitude. Object complements are usually adjectives or nouns.",
                    "answers": [
                        "strange",
                        "strangely"
                    ],
                    "correct": 0
                }
            ]
        }
    ]
}